Guide to the Theodore Paul Wright papers, 1911-1970
Wright, Theodore Paul papers, 1911-1970
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Theodore Paul Wright papers, 1911-1970
4-5-1381
Theodore Paul Wright, 1895-1970
31.9 cubic ft.
Correspondence, photographs, reports, clippings, bound volumes.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory correspondence; pamphlets, correspondence, photographs, reports, and clippings concerning aviation; and other papers reflecting Wright's career in aviation and at Cornell University. Also, four bound volumes of Theodore P. Wright's articles and addresses, 1918-1970.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Vice President for Research, Cornell University; president, Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory; president, Cornell Research Foundation; chairman of the executive committee, Cornell-Guggenheim Aviation Safety Center; chairman, Cornell Committee for Transportation Safety Research.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory correspondence; pamphlets, correspondence, photographs, reports, and clippings concerning aviation; and other papers reflecting Wright's career in aviation and at Cornell University. Also, four bound volumes of Theodore P. Wright's articles and addresses, 1918-1970.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Wright, Theodore P. (Theodore Paul, 1895-1970.; Cornell University.; Calspan Corporation.; Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory.
Subjects:
Aeronautics.; Aeronautics--Safety measures.; Transportation.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Chronologically arranged C.A.L. correspondence, 1966-1970 (Box 1)
- Chronologically arranged C.A.L. correspondence, 1966-1970 (Box 2)
- Mss. vols. re: Cornell Plantations, speed, aviation, research, set of bound vols.--"The Papers of H. Goddard.", c.1931-1959 (Box 3)
- Mss. vol. re: C.A.L., 1944-1969 (Box 4)
- Mss. vol. "Congratulations on Appointments, 1944-1948", 1944-1948 (Box 4)
- Mss. vol. "World Pollution" (Box 4)
- Misc. correspondence and pamphlets, 1968-1969, 1968-1969 (Box 4)
- Misc. correspondence and multi-copied reports, 1967, 1967-1970 (Box 5)
- Correspondence file re C.A.L., 1968-1970, 1968-1970 (Box 5)
- Subject file; misc. pamphlets, clippings and some alphabetically (chronologically) arranged correspondence), 1958-1967 (Box 6)
- File on aviation; pamphlets, clippings and photos. Also, this box contains a sketch book., 1953-1969 (Box 7)
- Subject file; alphabetically (chronologically) arranged correspondence, pamphlets, clippings, 1953-1961, 1962-1966, 1953-1966 (Box 8)
- Alpha. file, A - G, 1948-1967 (Box 9)
- Alpha. file, H - N, 1958-1970 (Box 10)
- Alpha. file, M - S; also: photos, pamphlets, multi-copied reports, 1959-1969 (Box 11)
- Alpha. file, S - Z, 1959-1968, 1952-1968 (Box 12)
- Subject file consisting mostly of clippings and pamphlets, 1952-1967., 1952-1967 (Box 12)
- Subject file consisting mostly of pamphlets and clippings; small amount of misc. correspondence, 1949-1963 (Box 13)
- Subject file consisting mostly of pamphlets and clippings; small amount of misc. correspondence, 1950-1968 (Box 14)
- Subject file consisting mostly of pamphlets and clippings. Inter-mixed is a small amount of correspondence (misc.), 1951-1967 (Box 15)
- Subject file of chronologically arranged correspondence. Inter-mixed are numerous pamphlets and clippings, 1956-1961 (Box 16)
- Subject file of chronologically arranged correspondence, and numerous pamphlets and clippings, 1937-1963 (Box 17)
- Subject file of chronologically arranged correspondence, numerous pamphlets, clippings and multi-copied reports., 1962-1968 (Box 18)
- Subject file of chronologically arranged correspondence. Also inter-mixed are pamphlets, clippings, notes, photos and multi-copied reports., 1943-1968 (Box 19)
- Subject file on T.P.W.--acting President at Cornell. Chronologically arranged correspondence., 1947-1968 (Box 20)
- Subject file consisting mainly of pamphlets and clippings, with a small amount of misc. correspondence, 1956-1965 (Box 21)
- Subject file of pamphlets, clippings and small amount of misc. correspondence, 1946-1967 (Box 22)
- Subject File of pamphlets, clippings and small amount of correspondence, 1947-1970 (Box 23)
- Contains misc. mss. vols. (7) and many misc. pamphlets, N.D., 1916-1945 (Box 24)
- Contains misc. mss. vols. (7) and misc. clippings, pamphlets, and correspondence (small amount), N.D., 1932-1950 (Box 25)
- Subject ile consisting mainly of pamphlets and clippings and inter-mixed is a small amount of misc. corres., 1957-1958 (Box 26)
- Misc. mss. vols., 1911-1912; Misc. pamphlets, 1965, 1911-1965 (Box 27)
- Subject file, containing: pamphlets, clippings and small amount of misc. correspondence, 1948-1969 (Box 28)
- Subject file containing: pamphlets, clippings, notes and small amounts of misc. correspondence, 1948-1969 (Box 29)
- Subject file, containing: pamphlets, clippings, notes and small amounts of correspondence, 1955-1963 (Box 30)
- Misc. mss. vols. (4) [i.e. literary figures], 1927-1949 (Box 31)
- Associated Universities, Inc. & Brookhaven National Laboratory, 1948-1967 (Box 32)
- Articles and addresses of T.P.W., 4 vols., 1918-1970 (Box 33)